<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-24T16:39:14+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Possum House Games</title><subtitle>Possum House is an indie development studio that focuses on small titles with experimental and fresh mechanics.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Monthly Dev Log!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/07/08/monthly-dev-log-july-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monthly Dev Log!" /><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/07/08/monthly-dev-log-july-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/07/08/monthly-dev-log-july-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;As always, the Possum House is a busy house. &lt;!--more--&gt;Nine development is off and running, Shot in the Dark is all but ready to go, and we’ve also been assisting with the Neuro;surge project in what free time we have left over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent this first month pinning down the Core gameplay loop while Dennis has been working to flesh out the look of the game. It has been a lot of fun to see him flex on some art again, exploring these really unique and fun maniacal mice enemies. He’s even using more than 3 colors this time around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lab.png&quot; alt=&quot;lab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proc gen has been a lot of fun to play with too. Other than that, the team has been focusing a lot on the main character, getting the movement game feel down as quick as we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;armory.png&quot; alt=&quot;armory&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also doing some work with the Neuro;surge project that has brought together a lot of local talent. Lesther has been doing his thing working under the hood messing with the programming while Dennis has been making the background all shiny and chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;nerolab.png&quot; alt=&quot;neurolab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of all that our pride and joy Shot in the Dark is all but locked and loaded. We have sent out all of our pitches to publishers, made some final tweaks, and now all that is left to do is to sit… and wait… S’gonna be fiiiine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we do have our back up plan in place and ready to go, so one way or another Shot in the Dark will be here soon~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month is looking to be just as busy too if not more so. Because on top of everything else the Possum House will also be hosting Chill Jam 2 the weekend of 7/11. So Come hangout and make some games!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/jam/chill-jam-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;chill-jam-2-export.png&quot; alt=&quot;chill-jam-2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;./assets/images/team/PossumLesther.png&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kpable&quot;}</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">As always, the Possum House is a busy house.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Monthly Dev Log!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/06/01/monthly-dev-log-june-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monthly Dev Log!" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/06/01/monthly-dev-log-june-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/06/01/monthly-dev-log-june-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey all Denny Here! Lots of big things are happening this month at the Possum House so lets jump in. &lt;!--more--&gt; It’s been a crazy sprint the past few weeks but we just wrapped up the development of Shot in the Dark! There are still some minor tweaks and adjustments to be made and we’d like to do a smudge more play testing, but yea… game’s done. So we are going to take the summer to polish and tweak as well as pitch to publishers. So yeah, we’ve made it to the end of the road and we are super proud and super tired and ready for a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too bad we are getting right back to work first thing Monday (yes this Monday as in today Monday). I am super proud to announce that we will be working with Rohit Crasta on his new project 9! Lesther will be assisting with the programming and I’ll be handling the art! We are super excited to be a part of this project full of maniacal mechanical mice plotting to steal the moon. For its cheese. It’s going to be a good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what we will be up to this summer, you will be hearing more from us soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Hey all Denny Here! Lots of big things are happening this month at the Possum House so lets jump in.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Monthly Dev Log!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/05/04/monthly-dev-log-may-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monthly Dev Log!" /><published>2020-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/05/04/monthly-dev-log-may-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/05/04/monthly-dev-log-may-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;Big News this month!&lt;!--more--&gt;Back in November of 2019 Shot in the Dark was accepted into an Incubator Program at the RIT MAGIC Center. We learned and accomplished so much over the past few months, but with the Incubator program wrapping up soon, Possum House Games is looking forward to what is coming up next. After some long talks and what not we’ve decided to take the summer to pitch to publishers. With their help, we would be able to reach a much wider audience and get additional support for even more Shot in the Dark content! Taking this extra time over the summer also means we don’t have to rush the game out the door, so we can properly polish the game and we also don’t have to leave cool content on the cutting room floor (like those creepy cool mysterious birbs). Taking this time means we can give our game the proper shot (HEH) it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other big news the Possum House is growing! Friend and regular collaborator &lt;a href=&quot;/team/lester.html&quot;&gt;Lesther “Kpable” Reynoso&lt;/a&gt; is officially joining the team as the resident programmer and developer! You may recognize him from previous Possum House chats and other projects. We worked together to develop Heavy is the Crown back in October and have been collaborating ever since. From one hour game jams, hot fixing Shot in the Dark bugs, to just hanging out and spitballing game ideas. So yea we are excited to be working together from here on out to bring you our weird offbeat brand of nonsense to the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that being said Shot in the Dark itself is in a really good place! The game itself is done and sitting comfortably at 90 plus handcrafted levels. So right now we are just cleaning things up and tying up loose ends. So even if we don’t snag a publisher Shot in the Dark will still be done and ready to go soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month we spent a good chunk of time sorting out much of what was discussed above. But we also got started on those good good achievements. Where we task the player to take our already difficult game, and do it the hard way. Yeah, we are cool like that. So we’ll be wrapping that up and a bunch of other stuff this month including but certainly not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again, those achievements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making the UI all pretty (and make sense)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Squashing all of the bugs (like that weird wiggly ghost that keeps popping up…)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding those cool creepy mysterious birbs (so excited for the birbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Big News this month!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shot in the Dark in PC Gamer!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/03/20/shot-in-the-dark-in-pc-gamer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shot in the Dark in PC Gamer!" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/03/20/shot-in-the-dark-in-pc-gamer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2020/03/20/shot-in-the-dark-in-pc-gamer.html"></content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Shot in the dark got a mention in PC Gamer!!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sword and the Slime in PC Gamer!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/10/07/sword-and-the-slime-in-pc-gamer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sword and the Slime in PC Gamer!" /><published>2019-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/10/07/sword-and-the-slime-in-pc-gamer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/10/07/sword-and-the-slime-in-pc-gamer.html"></content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">The Sword and the Slime was mentioned in PC Gamer!!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s HERE!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/10/04/its-here.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s HERE!" /><published>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/10/04/its-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/10/04/its-here.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image main&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/the_sword_and_the_slime/titlewater.gif&quot; alt=&quot;titlewater&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a weird long winding road but its finally here! The Sword and the Slime is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1130570/The_Sword_and_the_Slime/&quot;&gt;STEAM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://possumhousegames.itch.io/the-sword-and-the-slime&quot;&gt;ITCH.IO&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And oh boy it’s kind of a big deal for me. The Sword and the Slime is by far the biggest project that I have been a part of, let alone finished. But there is even more to it than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sword and the Slime itself has been in development off and on for the past 3-4 years, but the entire process was more like the culmination of 5-7 years of work because it wasn’t just the time it took to make the game, but also how long it took me to learn how to make a game. From game jams, small projects, ideas that went nowhere, to learning visual coding, pixel art, and animation, it was a lot to take in and I’ve still got plenty more I’m looking to learn. Then, on top of that, the games structure and direction changed significantly during development. For the longest time it was just “that game I’ve been working on” and “it will come out eventually”. There were plenty of times where I wondered myself if “eventually” was ever going to happen. The Sword and the Slime had slowly become this really big… thing, that was looming over me. I really wanted to move past it, just drop it and work on other stuff, I didn’t want to leave yet another project unfinished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately I believed that The Sword and the Slime was something worth seeing through to the end and sharing. And no small part of that is thanks to you guys. I’ve always been pretty hard on myself and my work, but seeing peoples reactions, feedback, and love for this weird little thing I made over the past few years has all kinds of kept me going. So for real, thank you :&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now its done! Right now, TODAY, you can go play my quirky, weird, but wholly unique little game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah. Tired, proud, ready for a nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not done. Going to take a little bit of a break, and keep an eye on bug reports, but I’m actually really really eager to hit the ground running on my next project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Its been a weird long winding road but its finally here! The Sword and the Slime is available on STEAM and ITCH.IO!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s Finally Happening!</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/08/02/its-finally-happening.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s Finally Happening!" /><published>2019-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/08/02/its-finally-happening</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/08/02/its-finally-happening.html">&lt;p&gt;The Sword and the Slime finally has an official launch date! It will be released October 4, 2019 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1130570/The_Sword_and_the_Slime/?fbclid=IwAR0tNXO2gh1hMPAOM2TgNoigUGGQl1YbnwTdvNoxyG8rCeoSYztQy_Mfpls&quot;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;. Wishlist us today!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re around the Rochester area, we’ll be celebrating our launch at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1130570/The_Sword_and_the_Slime/?fbclid=IwAR0tNXO2gh1hMPAOM2TgNoigUGGQl1YbnwTdvNoxyG8rCeoSYztQy_Mfpls&quot;&gt;Rochester Game Festival&lt;/a&gt; the follow day, October 5th. Swing by to say hi or to try out the game before you buy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who has supported us throughout the process, even those who just happened to swing by our table at a show. It’s been a long time coming and we couldn’t have done it without all the feedback and encouragement we’ve received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy our little game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/the_sword_and_the_slime/bombskeleton.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bombskeleton&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">The Sword and the Slime finally has an official launch date! It will be released October 4, 2019 on Steam. Wishlist us today!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sword Before the Slime</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/04/17/the-sword-before-the-slime.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sword Before the Slime" /><published>2019-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/04/17/the-sword-before-the-slime</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/04/17/the-sword-before-the-slime.html">&lt;p&gt;Since I’ll be wrapping up development soon there won’t be much content for a dedicated devlog. So instead I’ll be doing a series of post mortems reflecting on the development of Sword and the Slime. To kick things of we’ll start at the beginning.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the beginning there was no slime in The Sword and the Slime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I had been to three or so game jams, had a few game concepts that didn’t go anywhere, and had not written a single line of code (I still haven’t). The original idea of this game was more serious in tone and the sword would have been bound to different characters, and if you strayed too far from them the sword would lose its magical power and fall useless to the floor. The intro would have been an “on rails” experience following a world weary, but still powerful, wizard on his last hurrah to stop some calamity or some such. It would be your job to follow him around and protect him as he did his thing and casts this big ol’ mcguffin spell to save the world. But he still dies at the end, very dramatic, very sad, you all would have cried I promise. After all this the sword falls and is left in the dungeon for countless years… only to be found again by a lost and defenseless youth in the dungeon. From that point on the sword would be bound to the kid who would follow the sword, giving the player more direct control of the game. The rest writes itself, protect the kid because you have to not because you want to, fight scary monsters yada yada, guide them through the dungeon, growing bond and trust… would have been great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as it turns out creating a dynamic and convincing AI is tough. Who knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a good and proper game dev I kicked that core design issue down the road. I was sure I’d figure it out eventually. In the meantime, the “kid” placeholder sprite was a green block. And it was dumb. I mean really dumb. It had the bare minimum amount of functionality. So sure, it would follow the sword around no problem, even if it was off a cliff or into open flame or a maw of pointy bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there I was watching this dumb green block sprint off of cliffs while I contemplated the daunting task of creating a dynamic and responsive character. Watching this pitiful display I thought the green block looked a bit like a generic green slime cube. I giggled at thought and dismissed it. Then I did a double take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it was a slime it would be easier to program… it was practically done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it was a slime it could eat things&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could grow as it eats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could shrink as it took damage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s size would become a natural health indicator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could bounce and jiggle and then some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I thought about it the better it was. Not only did it sound way more fun and original, but more importantly it would cut down on design complexity. The only new problem was tying a flying sword and slime together into a narrative, but that would be much easier to figure out. I’ve learned (the hard way, several times) that so much of game design is knowing what not to do, and when to cut your losses. Even if it means taking a project in a radically different direction. That being said I’ve still been working on this game on and off for 3 plus years, it is scary to think how far along it would be now if I had stuck to my guns… Looking back I’m glad I made the call I did, and not just for the time and effort saved because The Sword and the Slime is so much better for it, having become this weird silly playful thing.
&lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/the_sword_and_the_slime/forest-scene.png&quot; alt=&quot;forest-scene&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Since I’ll be wrapping up development soon there won’t be much content for a dedicated devlog. So instead I’ll be doing a series of post mortems reflecting on the development of Sword and the Slime. To kick things of we’ll start at the beginning.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pixel by Pixel</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/02/15/pixel-by-pixel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pixel by Pixel" /><published>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/02/15/pixel-by-pixel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/02/15/pixel-by-pixel.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;graveyard.png&quot; alt=&quot;graveyard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;You may have heard I have an art show coming up. This isn’t my first art show, but this is my first pixel art show, so I wanted to talk about what pixel art means to me, an artist who originally started off as a traditional illustrator. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A crazy thing happens with pixel art. At first, it’s just this blocky and ugly thing, right? But then you start to play with it, to learn its restrictions and lean into them, and suddenly really really cool things start to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I come from a traditional art background: painting, illustration, and comics. So I know a thing or two about color, composition, and all that good stuff (at least my Bachelor’s degree says I do). But for me, pixel art has always felt like a completely different process. It’s like I’m a kid stuck with some very limited toys; here you go, you can play with some squares, nope, you just get squares. Okay, you can have some different colored squares, but that’s it. Have fun. Ironically, I find these restrictions very comforting, because a blank canvas is beyond intimidating on a good day. With pixel art, I always have one square to start with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;building.png&quot; alt=&quot;building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;When it comes to pixel art, I’m a fan of a particular style–that low low resolution stuff. Characters only 10 pixels tall kind of stuff. With a limited color palette–none of that gradient fade business. Just smooth, flat, color planes. Less is more. And don’t get me wrong, I love the high-res detail stuff too. But ultimately, with low-res art, there’s this extra interpretive element when the lack of detail gives our brains just enough wiggle room to fill in the blanks. That contrast that’s created where all of a sudden a little mess of blocks gets interpreted as a busy skyline complete with trains and traffic and little people living little lives in little itty bitty windows. And then you animate it and it gets even crazier. These harsh, blocky lines start to flow and stretch and bounce and yet it’s still a pile of harsh little squares. It’s that contrast that drives me nuts and I love it. When looking at a good piece of pixel art I often find myself thinking, “that is just so damn…clever.” This is why pixel art grabbed me in a way no other medium has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;windmill.png&quot; alt=&quot;windmill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;That’s what this show represents; how pixel by pixel, I started building shapes, asking questions, adding, subtracting, experimenting with different colors, moving things around. Each of these pieces started with that one little square and with me, getting to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROC Game Dev Space &amp;amp; Art Opening of “Pixel by Pixel” the Art of Dennis McCorry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, February 23, 2019, 6PM-9PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sibley Square, 250 E. Main St. Rochester, NY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/280977112578849/&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/280977112578849/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;field.png&quot; alt=&quot;field&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">You may have heard I have an art show coming up. This isn’t my first art show, but this is my first pixel art show, so I wanted to talk about what pixel art means to me, an artist who originally started off as a traditional illustrator.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The story so far</title><link href="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/01/15/the-story-so-far.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The story so far" /><published>2019-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/01/15/the-story-so-far</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://possum.loca.lt/blog/2019/01/15/the-story-so-far.html">&lt;p&gt;What was originally intended as a quick concept project between two friends gradually grew and spread and festered, eventually taking over my life and the lives of those around me.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t already know The Sword and the Slime is a non traditional puzzle platformer where the player, using only the mouse, controls a magical flying sword on a quest through deep dungeons and enchanted forests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been working on this project in our free time for the past three years and a lot has changed in that time. There used to be an evil wizard in the game? Voice acting was almost a thing at one point. There weren’t even any slimes in the game when we got started…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have seen us at a few events in the Rochester area–we even made it up to Toronto for TCAF last year (fingers crossed for this year), however we’ve otherwise kept a fairly low profile. But through all of that we have refined the game and are ready to start sharing more of our progress with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;image fit&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;20181117-MakerFaire.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Denny MakerFaire&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Denny at the Rochester Maker Faire – November 2018&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>denny</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">What was originally intended as a quick concept project between two friends gradually grew and spread and festered, eventually taking over my life and the lives of those around me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://possum.loca.lt/assets/images/logos/card.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>